welcome canaan's arena
in this video let us discuss about
the industrial credit and investment
corporation
of india or the icici
the ic ici was established
in the year 1955 as a public limited
company
under the indian companies act
and it was established with the main
objective
of providing medium-term and long-term
project financing to indian businesses
for the purpose of developing medium and
small
industries especially in the private
sector
the icici has been established
for the purpose of assisting industries
in the private sector by undertaking
the following functions as
assisting in creation expansion
and modernization of such enterprises
and then encouraging and promoting
private
ownership expansion of investment market
and also for providing finance in the
form of
long term and medium term loans
and also for underwriting issue of
shares and avengers making funds
available for reinvestment
and then for furnishing managerial
technical
and administrative services to the
indian industry
and also to extend guarantee for
deferred
payments in
1994 the icici bank
was established by the icici
as its wholly owned subsidiary with
the registered office at vadodara
in gujarat and corporate office at
mumbai in maharashtra
in 1999 it became the first
indian company and the first financial
institution from
non-japan asia to be listed on the new
york
stock exchange and
after that the parent company icici
merged with its subsidiary company icici
bank the icici bank
has contributed to the setting up of a
number of
indian institutions to establish
financial structure
in the country it has supported along
with other
institutions for setting up of the
national stock exchange
the christian which is india's first
professional credit rating
agency and then ncdex
that is the national commodities and
derivatives exchange
then edi or the entrepreneurship
development
institute of india that was set up in
and the nedfi that is the eastern
development of finance cooperation
that was also promoted by the national
level institutions
including icici
the icici group companies include
icici prudential life insurance company
icici securities icici lombard
general insurance company
the icic prudential amc and trust
icic venture icic direct
the icici home finance company limited
icici foundation and
disha financial counselling
so that's all about the industrial
credit
and investment corporation of india
limited that is
icici thank you for watching this video
for more videos subscribe the channel